hello everyone and welcome to the legal
power hour where we Jam 60 Minutes of
thought provoking discussion into a 30-
minute show designed to inform awaken
and protect our fellow American
citizens H Tom Scott and Sarah aiti and
today it is in Absolut pleasure to have
with us is our guest Arlington Virginia
former C CIA
officer and New York Times bestselling
author Kaku Welcome to our show John
thanks thanks good to be with
you absolutely um a pleasure to have you
on if you could
um viewers can we get the cliff version
summary of your life of um viewers who
haven't heard about you can you tell us
how you went from your
life sure uh it's a long story and I'll
make it very very short uh I joined the
CIA in January of 1990 as an analyst
working in the director of intelligence
uh I worked on Iraq for about seven and
a half years got bored and um switch to
um operations to counterterrorism
operations specifically it was a very
unusual switch at the time
um served several more than several
overseas
tours after September 11th I became the
chief of CIA counterterrorism operations
in Pakistan and in that role uh led a
series of raids that resulted in the
capture of Abu zubeda who the CIA
believed at the time was the number
three in al-Qaeda I returned to
headquarters then to become the
executive assistant to the cia's deputy
director for operations
and I left the CIA in mid 2004 to go
into the private sector now AB was a
Beta had been uh tortured uh in a secret
CIA facility I was asked before that
torture began if I wanted to be trained
in what the CIA was calling the use of
enhanced interrogation techniques I said
that I had an ethical and legal problem
with that I thought that it was a
torture program I thought that it was
illegal it was certainly unethical and
immoral and I declined as it turned out
I was the only one of 14 people
approached who declined to be trained uh
but I kept the secret to myself for many
years actually and then finally after I
left the CIA in December of 2007 Brian
Ross of ABC News asked if um I would
come on his show he said that he had a
source who said that I had tortured
abuaba I said that was absolutely untrue
I was the only person who was kind to
Abu Zeda I never touched AA or any other
prisoner and he said well you're welcome
to come on the show and defend
yourself well President Bush in the
meantime was lying directly to the
American people by looking in the camera
and saying we do not torture I knew that
that was a lie and then finally he said
that if there was torture it was the
result of a rogue CIA
officer and I knew that was a lie and I
thought well by God they're going to try
to pin this on me I'm going to just come
clean and I'm going to tell the truth
and I called Brian Ross and I said I'll
do your interview and I decided that no
matter what he asked me I would tell the
truth and so I did and I said three
things in that interview I said that the
CIA was torturing its prisoners I said
that torture was official US government
policy it was not the result of a rogue
and I said that the policy had been
personally approved by the president of
the United
States So within 24 hours the FBI began
investigating me
uh they investigated me for one whole
year from December 2007 to December 2008
and then in December 2008 They concluded
that I had not committed a crime and
they closed the case against me a month
later January 2009 Barack Obama is
inaugurated Barack Obama the most
transparent president in history I might
add what I did not know was that the CIA
had secretly asked Obama to reopen the
case against me and so for the next
three years the FBI was uh in my emails
they were tapping my phones I was under
FBI
surveillance and then in January of 2012
I was charged with five felonies coming
out of that original interview including
three counts of Espionage the the
gravest crime with which an American can
be charged and which in many cases
carries with it the death
penalty so I fought those charges for uh
for 10 months I was facing 45 years in
prison which essentially is a death
sentence I'm I'm 53 years old and so um
eventually the government came back when
they finally understood that I was
willing to go to trial and I was willing
to testify on my own behalf and talk
about some of the Hideous things that I
had witnessed in my 15 years at the CIA
they came back with an offer of 30
months of which I would serve
23 um I actually turned that offer down
and then one of my 11 lawyers pulled me
aside and said listen this can be a blip
in your life or it can be the defining
event of your life I urge you to make it
the blip he said if you were my brother
I would beg you to take this deal and
then another one of my attorneys said
you seem to think that this is about
right or wrong innocence or guilt it's
not it's about cutting your losses the
government doesn't lose its cases it's
not going to get any better than this
and so I took the deal and then I got
out after 23 months and um and I've
tried to move on since
then John that's that's unbelievable I
mean I'm still floored at what you've
been through I mean I wouldn't wish it
on anybody not my worst enemy I can only
imagine um can you tell our viewers what
you've been up to since you've gotten
out of prison sure I um I'm trying to
patch something together and I think
I've I think I've succeeded I have two
books that have come out since I got
home one is called doing time like a spy
how the CIA taught me to survive and
thrive in prison and it's a collection
of blogs that I wrote for prison which I
got in serious trouble for but continued
to do I wrote 19 of them um and and sort
of a a howto book um the dirty tricks
that the CIA taught me to use in
training that I was able to use in
prison to keep myself safe uh and the
second one is the convenient terrorist
it's a book I wrote with Joe Hickman a
former Guantanamo guard when when the
CIA turned over custody of abuaba to the
military it was to Joe Hickman so I
wrote half the book Joe wrote half the
book and it came out last month I also
have a a weekly syndicated column uh
that runs on readers supported news.org
and you
know Washington has a reputation as
being the city of Second Chances there's
no second chance for me in Washington
but there is a second chance for me in
Los Angeles and since I've been home
I've sold three different television
shows to three different networks one
with Oliver Stone um one with Alec
Baldwin and one with uh the director
Simon West who won an Academy Award for
Blackhawk Down the show I sold with
Simon has actually gone to Pilot and so
I seem to find myself as a television
writer now so you know little by little
I've patched something together and it's
turned out to be a decent living that's
amazing it's certainly not CIA work I
can tell you that you take an oath of
office to
defend and then you take an oath of
office to defend um you know security
and confidenti
and everything else well when those two
are in Conflict yeah right what if if
the oath that you took to the US
Constitution is in conflict and the oath
that you
took is in Conflict you have to defer to
the higher authority absolutely which is
the US contitution
absolutely absolutely you defend the
Constitution that's the that's the
underlying fabric of our of our nation
so I just don't you know I don't get it
it's just in you know again the two sets
of rules you know for for John kiraka
there's one set of rules for Hillary
Clinton there's another set of rules
what's your feeling on that and how does
I mean I'm upset just observing it never
mind living it you know what I mean what
what is what would you what do you have
to say at that Hillary Clinton should
have gone to prison for a very long time
plain and simple uh but you're
absolutely right Tom there are two
completely separate sets of rules if you
es especially under the Obama
Administration I think Obama was
probably the the wor worst offender of
of of recent presidents although George
HW Bush was pretty bad too um but if you
were a friend of the president or you
had four shiny stars on your shoulder
you're gonna get away with murder you
know General um General Campbell who
leaked the fact that that the US
intelligence Community had created the
stuck net virus he leaked that to the
New York Times because he was bragging
about his own role in the creation of
the stet virus he was a Ed he was
charged with a felony a account of
Espionage he was found guilty and before
he was even sentenced President Obama
pardoned him why because according to
the New York Times he was quote the
president's favorite
General well if you're the president's
favorite general or the president's
favorite whatever or a friend of the
president you're gonna get off now I was
convicted I took a plea to confirming
the name of a former CIA colleague to a
journalist the journalist never revealed
the name the name was never made public
all right General Petraeus leaked the
names of 10 covert operatives to his
adulterous
girlfriend but because he was a friend
of the president he was charged only
with one misdemeanor count of
mishandling classified information he
got 18 months of unsupervised
probation and never served a single hour
in jail not a single hour the day after
his sentencing he went to Iraq on a
mission for the White House he actually
got to keep his security
clearance so the the hypocrisy to me is
utterly sickening you know I told Sarah
earlier off camera before we started um
recording the show that I try very hard
to not be bitter to not be angry because
it doesn't help me in any way to be to
be
angry but this makes me angry because
the justice system is not
just you know African-Americans often
say that the justice system is exactly
that it's just us well you know I feel
the same way I feel like I got screwed
by my government and Tom you make a very
important Point here and that a point
that point is when anything whether it's
a law or a policy or a signed secrecy
agreement is in conflict with the
Constitution the Constitution wins out
every time on my very first day at the
CIA I put my right hand in the air and I
swore to uphold and to protect the
Constitution against all enemies
domestic and
foreign now I I can't believe that I was
the only one of the 300 or 400 people in
that Auditorium that day who took that
oath seriously
but I did I took it seriously without
the Constitution we have nothing we have
chaos it's the Constitution that makes
this a great country it's the
Constitution that allows us to believe
in things like American
exceptionalism well I took that very
seriously y well like you just said it's
not just uh threats abroad it's domestic
I mean that's that's the whole when we
get sworn in it's domestic and sometimes
that's the greater threat you know um I
think we should be policemen of the
world and I don't think we should be
doing all these things internationally
that we are unless we're asked for help
but you know certainly
100% the government starts and you know
with the whole thing with these
prosecutors and this is one of my cases
that I have Going Back East right now
against an attorney Joseph mot who's
committed d a bunch of felonies in a
particular case he's committed state and
federal crimes perjury obstruction of
Justice a conspiracy now I'm I'm trying
to get the attention of the FBI and the
doj which I don't know if that's going
to happen or not but you know a
prosecutor does not have to Pro I mean I
could murder somebody and if they don't
want to prosecute
me they call it prosecutorial discretion
yeah prosecutorial discretion absolutely
absolutely absolutely and if they want
to prosecute someone for spitting on the
sidewalk or smoking in public someone
like you you kind of just said with the
general you know betray us you know 10
major instances of uh leaks of security
and they turn a blind eye they have that
prerogative so um one of thing I want to
ask too is um the prison industrial
complex which we write about in our book
that's you know there's many many
problems in the system no competition is
probably number one but what do you
think of the prison industrial complex
the privatization of Prisons the police
state that we're in right
now wow I think this is one of the major
problems facing our country today uh wow
where do I even begin you know the
United States has 5% of the world's
population and 25% of the world's prison
population now most of those prisoners
something like 92% of them are in local
and state jails and prisons so reform
which is absolutely necessary it has to
begin at the local and the state level
um there's a wonderful book that came
out in 2012 written by Dr Harvey
silverglate who's a professor of law at
Harvard University the book is called
three felonies a day and silverglate
argues that we are so over legislated in
this country so over regulated and over
criminalized that the average American
on the average day going about his or
her normal Daily Business commits three
felonies
so if they want to get you they're going
to get you and there's nothing you can
do about it I've I've written
extensively about cases like a fisherman
who caught a a hell it that was too
small uh well instead
of keeping it on board and letting it
die and taking it into port to measure
it to determine that it was too small he
threw it back in the ocean well somebody
saw him throw it back in the ocean do
you know that that's a
felony it's a felony and he was charged
with a felony and had to go all the way
to the Supreme Court of the United
States now he eventually won but how
many millions of dollars of the
taxpayers money was wasted to prosecute
this fisherman for throwing a fish back
in the water there was a woman who
worked for the National Oceanic and
Atmospheric Administration in Hawaii who
was charged with a felony count of
interfering with the feeding of a wife
wild animal for whistling at a whale she
whistled at a whale as it was eating a
seal and the FBI uh decided that it was
necessary to break down the door of her
house at six o'clock in the morning to
haul her out and confiscate all of her
electronics and all of her business
records and she was utterly ruined she
ended up taking a a plea to a
misdemeanor a misdemeanor charge of
violating The Endangered Species Act or
some nonsensical thing
uh but is this really the way that we
need to to prosecute cases in this
country do do these people really need
to be in prison is society better off
having the fisherman and and this woman
from Noah in prison I think not
now my experience uh was in the federal
system it's my understanding that
private prisons are far far worse than
government uh prisons and it's because
of the the profit motive the only way
for private prison companies to make
money is to um save money on food and on
Medical Care I've written extensively
about this so you have people dying
literally dying in prison because
they're they're not getting Medical Care
uh well you know they are bad people in
prison but most of them don't have a
death uh death penalty uh case and
whether the government likees it or not
at whatever level local state or federal
they have to take care of these people
now I I personally believe that we made
a a terrible mistake during the Reagan
Administration and extending through the
Clinton Administration Bill Clinton
actually made it far worse um with this
so-called War on
Drugs what we did is we
incarcerated an entire generation of
people you know when when one out of
every four black men in this country is
either in prison in jail on probation or
on parole there's a problem and in the
meantime the government's done nothing
to restrict the flow of drugs into this
country
so that coupled with the fact that
they've phased out um educational
programs they've phased out training
programs they phased out counseling and
therapy all you're doing is you're just
incarcerating people and all that's
going to do is piss them off and
eventually they're going to get out and
they're going to go back home and
they're going to be angry and they're
going to be broke and they can't read
and they can't write and they have no
job skills and what do you think they're
going to do they're going to return to a
life of
crime so the money is better spent on
education and on training and on drug
and alcohol therapy than on
incarcerating more and more and more
people and hoping that you can just
arrest and prosecute everybody who's
broken a law the entire system is broken
from the prosecutors to the judges to
the prison administrators it's
broken John what are some of your
suggestions as to how to address our our
broken legal system first I think we
have to decriminalize and indeed I think
we have to legalize
marijuana you can't imagine the people
who are doing hideous stretches of time
on charges related to marijuana I'll
give you an example and this is just an
anecdote but this is something that that
has really stuck with me there was a guy
in my housing unit who who arrived about
a year after I got
there his family never missed a single
weekend he had a lovely wife and three
beautiful children and they visited him
every single Saturday and I asked him
one day what are you in for and he said
I got caught trans uh
transporting 12 pounds of marijuana and
I said what did you get he said they
gave me 12 and a half years and it
wasn't even his he said he was he was
being paid to Move It from point A to
point B he was a
mule and I said 12 years for Weed really
and he said yeah 12 years he said to
make matters worse he said I had a
successful heating and air conditioning
company and I employed 10 people so he
said when I got arrested and prosecuted
not only did it ruin my family and he
said for that I take responsibility but
I lost my business in this isolated
rural area in Pennsylvania and 10 people
were thrown out of
work so is society really better off
because this guy's locked up for 12
years for having marijuana in his car I
think not the first thing we need to do
is is end this ridiculous War on Drugs
we need to legalize marijuana and treat
it like alcohol sell it in liquor stores
have the government tax it it's not
addictive it causes less uh uh harm than
cigarettes or than than alcohol it
should be legal that's the first thing
the second thing is we need very very
serious sentencing reform now there has
been a bipartisan Bill in Congress since
2015 it has passed committees in both
the house and the Senate when the
Democrats ran the Congress and when the
Republicans ran the Congress But Eric
Holder was against it and Jeff sessions
is against it and so neither uh Harry
Reid nor Mitch McConnell would allow it
to come to the floor of the senate for a
vote okay this has bipartisan support
and it would be to reform the sentencing
laws and to do away with most mandatory
minimum sentences you know we've got the
sentences now where you can be a
firsttime non-violent drug offender
first time nonviolent drug offender and
get 10 years 20 years 30 years in prison
first
time there's no second chance now if you
have attacked and raped a child yes you
should die in prison if there's violence
in your case definitely if there's a gun
in your case sure you should be in
prison but if you're out there smoking
weed or maybe you get caught for the
very first time you're manufacturing
meth or something or you have a
substance of abuse
problem uh you shouldn't be in prison at
least not for these ridiculous stretches
of time now another thing that needs to
be addressed right away at every level
of the uh of the prison industrial
system is that in our country for
whatever reason we treat mental illness
as a disciplinary problem rather than as
a medical one and so the prisons are
filled with with crazy people who should
be in hospitals not in prisons and I'll
give you another example one of my
cellmates was a guy named
James James um was on federal probation
he was homeless he was living in a
cardboard box under a bridge in
Pittsburgh and he violated the terms of
his probation just so that he could
spend the winter indoors right you
violate parole probation you do three
maybe four months uh uh inside well he
purposely violated in October so he
could spend November December January
and February
indoors have three Square meals a day
and maybe some medical care so he got to
uh to the prison this is three months be
uh three and a half months before I uh I
went home he got to the prison he was
assigned to myself and he came in his
first day put out his hand introduced
himself around hi guys I'm James this is
what I'm in
for and he said I'm gonna warn you about
something he said I am certifiably
insane he said I make no bones about it
I'm insane but if I'm on my medication
I'm okay if I'm off my medication I'm
going to apologize to you guys right now
I'm going to be nuts
well sure enough they wouldn't give his
give him his medication they saidwell
you're only here for four months this
medicine's expensive we don't want to
spend you know a thousand dollars a week
or whatever it was to give you your
medication so he had no medication well
guess what he went crazy and they ended
up doing what they do with all crazy
people they put him in solitary
confinement which made him even crazier
now the United Nations has declared the
American form of solitary confinement to
be a form of t torture which it is I'm
telling you it's torture and he went
even crazier in solitary so what did
they do to address his craziness in
solitary they stripped him naked they
beat him to a bloody pulp and they threw
him outside and I'm talking about in
January they threw him outside now I had
a friend who was in the cell next to him
Jesus who
was cellmate of of a friend of mine he
told me later that for the first hour or
so James cursed them from outside in the
snow and then for the second hour he
apologized he asked them to let him back
in then he cried and begged them to let
him back in and finally he curled up
into a ball and he fainted and finally
once he was unconscious that's when they
brought him back in well guess what
that's illegal that's a felony that's
torture but that goes on in American
prisons every single day and there's no
recourse it's just like you see in
Orange is the New Black who you going to
believe a law enforcement officer or
some convicted
criminal that's that's chilling and
um that the like you just said it you
know who you going to believe the law
enforcement or the convicted felon and
that's that happens in court and you
know we write about that as well they're
going to certainly believe a law
enforcement officer's word somehow a
badge magically adds credibility to
testimony right that's going on in
prison right now is as far as the
torture and Isis I mean no that's no not
at
all yeah one thing one thing I want to
ask you too John
is from the Washingtonian and this might
have to do with the what you just
address somewhat it says everyone with
authority in prison is lying can you
elaborate on that a little bit is that
kind of kind of what you were just
talking about right now yes um in part
that is what I'm uh talking about
um I got in trouble one time because I
was having a phone call with my wife and
of course all calls are recorded and my
calls in particular they would listen to
Live just because I was a I was a
high-profile troublemaker and so I told
my wife that uh I said you know every
Everybody I've met in here and I mean
from the guards to the administrators to
the warden himself they're all
degenerate Liars well as soon as I hung
up the phone I was called to the
Lieutenant's office I was berated for
for saying that they were all degenerate
liars and I I looked at the guy said but
you are you lie to us every single day
every word that comes out of your mouth
is a lie and I said you know I was
eligible for for nine months of halfway
house the warden told me that he would
recommend me for nine months of halfway
house he didn't he lied he recommended
me for five months of halfway house well
my unit manager told me that my five
months was what I had coming to me it
was mandatory that I got five months it
was my minimum of of uh halfway house
time which in my case would be converted
into house arrest but that was a lie uh
what happened was in the in the
sentencing computation office in Texas
they decided that I was so much of a
pain in their ass that they weren't
going to give me any halfway house time
at all so I said you guys lied to me at
every single level so the maximum amount
of time that I could have spent
in prison was 23 months and I spent 23
months finally the warden approached me
after lunch one time one day out outside
the cafeteria am I allowed to swear on
this uh
show sure yeah I'm gonna recount the the
conversation exactly as it took place
the warden pulled me aside and he said
hey I know that you called me a liar but
uh I said yeah I did you know I I'm
sorry if you're offended by that but but
you did lie to me and everybody's lied
to me and he says well you know why they
you don't you because you keep
writing that damn blog and I said
Warden 23 months 20 months 18 months
what's the difference I said I have gone
NOS to nose with Al-Qaeda with Hezbollah
with the Iranians with some stupid
divorce attorney do you think I'm afraid
of your prison to spend another two
months here or another five months here
I'm not not afraid of you guys you can't
do anything to me that hasn't already
been done and he just kind of harped and
walked away and that's how we left
it now let me add one more thing if you
are the Crooked wife of the chairman of
the house Judiciary Committee and you
get sentenced to 22 months in a camp
cupcake minimum security Camp you get 12
months of halfway house so you actually
only do 10 months in Camp cupcake and
the rest of the time you do it at
home wow that's the way it
works you know for a while there I I
wish that I was married to uh the
chairman of the house Judiciary
Committee I mean it's unbelievable I
mean has this whole experience
just made you see our government and oh
our legal system and a so so corrupt you
know what I did I I'm third generation
Democrat and uh and I ran screaming from
the Democratic party when this all
happened and I join the Libertarians and
I'm under No Illusion that the
Libertarians are going to win a
presidential race I I know that the
libertarian party is is a small party
but the Libertarians are the only ones
talking about these issues the
Libertarians are the only ones who were
talking about protecting and respecting
the
Constitution so I'll tell you another
thing um I I the in in the last election
that I was allowed to vote uh 2012 I
voted for Gary Johnson for president
Gary Johnson was the libertarian party's
nominee for president and he's the
former Republican governor of H New
Mexico I really believed in what Gary
Johnson was talking about well when I
got to prison i' had been in prison
about three weeks and lo and behold I
get a letter from Gary Johnson and he
says that he followed my case he thought
i' had been screwed and he wished that
there was some way that he could help me
I immediately wrote back told him I was
a big fan a supporter I had voted for
him in 2012 and thank you so much for
the kindness of paying attention to my
case what I did not know was that he had
also written a letter to Eric Holder
saying what's wrong with you let this
man go home so at least he can work and
support his family it was a very
generous thing to do and he didn't tell
me that he had done it learned about it
later through a Freedom of Information
Act request well when I got home from
prison two years later one of the first
calls that I received was from Gary
Johnson W and he said that uh he was
running for president again and he hoped
he could count on my support and I said
Governor I said I am with you all the
way and so I joined the board of the
libertarian party and I traveled with
Governor Johnson to 18 states uh on the
campaign in the three weeks before the
election we went to 18 states across the
the west and the Midwest everywhere from
kalamazo to Anchorage
Alaska and um I was a proud libertarian
I remain a proud libertarian you know
I've come to the conclusion and and I I
I've been a lifelong political animal
I've been in Washington since the week
after I turned 18 years old I'm very
very political I always have been but
I've come to the conclusion that on
these big thematic issues there's really
very little difference between the
Republicans and the Democrats you know
there are little differences around the
edges of these issues but in terms of
the big themes the big policies they're
essentially the same and they're both
corrupt and the only party that's
talking about freedom and liberty and
the rule of law and respect for the
Constitution and foreign
entanglements is the
Libertarians yeah yeah that's true I'm
actually a Libertarian myself so and for
the same reasons for the same reasons
you know the the Constitution gets used
as a dmat by the by the Republicans by
the
Democrats it really is no different you
got big government for individuals or
big government for corporations then you
go all the way to the other end of the
spectrum want basically no government
right I cut this out of today's Wall
Street Journal cops and robbers all
rolled into one this is an oped
on the use of um uh what do they call it
civil uh civil forfeiture right you can
be stopped uh for speeding let's say and
uh you've got $10,000 in your pocket
because you're going to go buy a used
car and the cop says why do you have
$110,000 you say I'm gonna go buy a used
car cop says I think you're a drug
Runner you've never been charged with
any crime you're just a guy driving down
the highway maybe you didn't even get a
ticket for speeding but he can legally
take your $10,000 that's called civil
asset forfeiture and and this piece
again this is in the Wall Street Journal
which is no liberal newspaper it says
that the federal government seized four
and a half billion dollars from people
who had never been charged with crimes
versus $3.9 billion dollar that robbers
stole from robbing people's homes and
and businesses the federal government is
actually responsible for stealing more
money out of our pockets than burglars
and robbers are responsible for
and and a big happened during the
Democrats too this is not just on Jeff
sessions this happened during Eric
Holder as well I wrote about it
extensively and this is what I mean when
I say on these big thematic issues
there's no difference between the
Democrats and the Republicans well as
Americans we should be up in arms over
this policy we should be in the streets
over this policy and we're not it's
horrible I mean I I've tweeted about it
I'm totally against it I mean it's one
thing if if you're convicted of a crime
and then the government comes in and and
takes your assets but now with the
program they have you don't even have to
be convicted no they just suspect it
they look you don't have to be even
formally accused gonna do a crime or
might do a crime and they take it I mean
that's a violation of your due process
it really is it's a constitutional
violation and it's it's appalling to me
and somehow the Supreme Court has not
found that and I don't know why I think
it's a
travesty well it might it might come up
before The Supreme Court you never know
I hope it
does now does that article John mention
the bill that's been recently introduced
by Senator ran
Paul no actually and I was disappointed
that it didn't um it's it's long on
numbers and um and a couple of examples
but it does not mention Rand Paul's uh
uh Bill no and it should it frankly it
should have been based on Rand Paul's
Bill like you to mention the books that
you've written while in prison and the
new one that you just launched and um
Sarah if there's anything else that
you'd like to ask John as well you know
I I want to say thank you to you for for
your honesty your integrity and for
agreeing to be very much a guest on our
show I mean your story is unbelievable
but believable in an odyssey sadly um
and it's just it's something that I
think every everybody needs to know
because like you said if somebody wants
to go after you and get you for
something they will they will people
need know that that this can happen to
anybody not to somebody who worked in
the government you know it can happen to
any normal average American and and
that's a message that I think we should
we should be um uh trying to explain
trying to to pass to your your viewers
that this can happen to anybody it's not
just me because I was in the CIA or Ed
Snowden because he was in NSA or
whatever it is this can happen to
absolutely any American if they don't
like you they don't like your politics
whatever the reason they don't like your
attitude they can dig deep enough that
they're going to find things to charge
you with and there's almost nothing you
can do about it so uh thank you both my
my books are doing time like a spy how
the CIA taught me to survive and thrive
in prison and the convenient terrorist
thanks for having me this was a lot of
fun thank you again John thank you AB
absolutely John and just to close for
our viewers I'd like to mention that
they can catch our show fresh every
first M Monday of the month in time I'll
you at any time afterward right here on
our YouTube channel also be sure to
subscribe to our blog where we discuss
not only the material we've discussed in
this show but other very
very topics as well which you can see at
www.st oi
YF and if you want to protect yourself
to the fullest extent possible against
our wildly corrupt legal
system of our book stack the legal odds
in your favor and please use the link
provided under this video as well as you
will be help as you will help support
our part partner Mr John kiraku as
well out that he's just kindly so shared
with us on this show so once again John
thank you very much for being on our
show it's been uh an exceptional and
informative discussion thank you so much
thanks for having me thank you John
thank you